is hemoglobin 17 too high my doctor half
my weekly dosage because of it no no too
high based on what right who who says
what's too high but no my local
hematologist when I was in uh Paris
doing Urology he didn't even blink you
know because he got people sent to him
all the time from other providers for
secondary ryos and we so we talk every
now and then about it and joke and he's
like he didn't even blink unless their
hemoglobin was over 20 at all and that's
rare honestly for it to be mine ran
about 18 when I was on injection so no
this and this this nonsense of just
reducing your dose like that's going to
suddenly magically fix the hematocrite
it doesn't it's still going to be high
higher than normal almost all these
things are going to be outside of the
normal range when you're taking
testosterone that's the other thing I'm
kind of Blown Away that providers
especially don't
Gras it's like they're okay with the
testost some of them are okay with
testosterone being higher than normal
but then anything else no we can't oh oh
your prolactin is two points above
normal well no kidding you're taking
testosterone exogenously oh your estrad
60 or 80 or whatever yeah you don't need
to be testing it but of course it's out
of normal those normal ranges weren't
made or validated with people taking
hormones those were Baseline levels and
that is just something that I don't know
why that's so hard to grasp we should
all understand that providers especially
should understand how lab ranges were
formed and made and then all bets are
off once you're taking an the exogenous
substance and this idea that there's
this ideal or optimal number within that
Baseline range has no bearing on reality
when you're taking a substance at all
[Music]